Jason Gomes

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER · BA (COMPUTER SCIENCE) · BS (INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY)

□732-675-1327 | ■JasonG7234@gmail.com | 🚳 www.jasongomes.me | 🖸 JasonG7234 | 🛅 Jason Gomes

Summary _____

Driven software engineer with 3 years of experience in full-stack development. Experience with software development & testing, inter-team communication, and mentorship. Strengths in both Python and Java along with a consistent desire to keep learning in an ever-evolving field.

Work Experience _____

iCIMS Holmdel, New Jersey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER II

- Employs Java 8 principles to refactor existing code and provide new features for HR SaaS company
- Rectifies critical severity production code causing memory leaks and thread-locking with SQL
- · Creates test plans in TestRail and TM4J platforms to reduce released bugs and boost customer satisfaction
- · Improves legacy front-end UI by creating and editing Single Page Applications with React and Redux
- · Provides enhanced API solutions to Amazon in order to meet growing GDPR requirements
- · Oversees and maintains Spring Boot microservices to reduce strain on Java monolith
- Automates Selenium Webdriver tests in Java to simplify multiple tests down to a button click

ShotQuality Remote

SENIOR FULL-STACK DEVELOPER May. 2021 - PRESENT

- Develops Python Flask REST API endpoints related to profile creation and statistic gathering
- Functions as Linux server administrator, including automating a Bash script to create a daily server build
- Runs SQL on production database to query accounts, delete users, and edit permissions
- · Automates profile creation via Stripe webhook to save an hour of daily manual account registrations
- · Implemented entire ShotQuality testing framework using Python's pytest and React's jest modules

L'OrealBerkeley Heights, New Jersey

HRIS ANALYST INTERN

- Redesigned L'Oreal-wide HRIS homepage using Microsoft Sharepoint software and HTML elements
- Collaborated on L'Oreal Anywhere mobile app development with Capriza software
- Created Windows batch files to automate manual data entry, file-moving, and internet navigation
- Wrote Visual Basic Excel macros to streamline weekly and quarterly file uploads

New Brunswick, New Jersey

Sep. 2015 - May. 2019

June. 2017 - August. 2017

Jun. 2018 - PRESENT

Education

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

B.A. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & B.S IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

- GPA: 3.66
- Extracurriculars: Undergraduate Student Alliance of Computer Scientists Mentor

Projects_____

NBA Draft Model Old Bridge, New Jersey

PYTHON WEB SCRAPER AND MACHINE LEARNING MODEL USED TO PREDICT UNDER-THE-RADAR NBA DRAFT PICKS

Nov. 2019

- Utilizes BeautifulSoup to parse websites and identify relevant statistics
- Organizes stats and CSV files with pandas and numpy to allow for easy data manipulation
- Graphs scatter plots and line graphs using matplotlib to visualize the data
- Creates a tensorflow neural network and a logistic regression model & a gradient boosting model with ML library sklearn for data analysis

Skills

Languages Java, Python, React, SQL, HTML, CSS, Bash, NodeJS

Frameworks Flask, Hibernate, Jest, JUnit, Redux, Spring Boot, Tensorflow, Webdriver

ToolsAtlassian Suite, AWS, Figma, Git, Jenkins, JMeter, NVDA, TM4J **Soft Skills**Agile Methodologies, Mentorship, Teamwork, Project Management

Hobbies Basketball, Chess, Fantasy Football, Tinkering